Guide to the Fred Meyer, Inc. collection 1922-2010
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Stores and Properties, 1922-2010; Series C
  - Oregon Stores, 1930-2000
    - Glisan Exterior and Construction, 1961 (Box-folder 14/9)
    - Glisan Grand Opening, 1961 (Box-folder 14/10)
    - Glisan Interior, circa 1980; 1997 (Box-folder 14/11)
    - Glisan's Eve's Restaurant, circa 1961 (Box-folder 14/12)
    - South Salem Grand Opening, circa 1968 (Box-folder 14/13)
    - South Salem Grand Opening Newspaper Section - Oversize (Original), 1976 (Box-folder OSD-3/2)
    - South Salem Grand Opening Newspaper Section - Oversize (Photocopy), 1976 (Box-folder OSC-1/9)
    - Gresham Interior, 1976 (Box-folder 15/1)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-024
    - Beaverton Interior, 1979 (Box-folder 15/2)
    - The Dalles Grand Opening, 1980 (Box-folder 15/3)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-025 through 199-028
    - Corvallis Interior, 1961 (Box-folder 15/4)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-029
    - Roseburg Grand Opening, 1984 (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Benson Plaza, circa 1987 (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Grants Pass Grand Opening and News Clippings, 1988; 2000 (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Grants Pass Grand Opening - Oversize News Clippings, 2000 (Box-folder OSD-3/2)
    - Hollywood West Store, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Tualatin Grand Opening and Interiors, 1980; 1997 (Box-folder 15/9)
    - Redmond Grand Opening, 1999 (Box-folder 15/10)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-031
    - Medford Grand Opening, 1999 (Box-folder 15/11)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-032
    - Oregon City Remodel, 1999 (Box-folder 15/12)
    - Cornelius Remodel, 1999 (Box-folder 15/13)
    - Canby Grand Opening, 2000 (Box-folder 15/14)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-030
    - Florence Grand Opening, 2000 (Box-folder 15/15)
    - Market Basket store, circa 1965 (Box-folder 36/2)
    - Oak Grove store Opening, 1960 (Box-folder 36/3)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-100.
    - Oak Grove store exterior and construction, circa 1960 (Box-folder 36/4)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-101
    - Oak Grove store interior, 1960 (Box-folder 36/5)
    - Oak Grove store interior, 1960 (Box-folder 36/5)
    - Peninsula store exterior, 1962 (Box-folder 36/6)
    - Peninsula store opening, circa 1962 (Box-folder 36/7)
    - Peninsula store interior, circa 1962 (Box-folder 36/8)
    - Raleigh Hills store opening, 1959 (Box-folder 36/9)
    - Raleigh Hills store exterior, 1961; 1997 (Box-folder 36/10)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-102.
    - Raleigh Hills store interior, 1959-1960; circa 1990 (Box-folder 36/11)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-103.
    - Raleigh Hills garden shop, 1961 (Box-folder 36/12)
    - Raleigh Hills store construction, circa 1959 (Box-folder 36/13)
    - Rockwood store construction, 1957 (Box-folder 36/14)
    - Rockwood store exterior, 1957 (Box-folder 36/15)
    - Rockwood store interior, circa 1959 (Box-folder 36/16)
    - Rockwood store openings, 1959; circa 1975 (Box-folder 36/17)
    - Rose City store openings, 1949; 1955 (Box-folder 36/18)
    - Rose City store exterior, 1949; 1955 (Box-folder 36/19)
    - Rose City store exterior drawings, circa 1949 (Box-folder 36/20)
    - Rose City store interior, 1949 (Box-folder 36/21)
    - Alder Street drug store, circa 1930 (Box-folder 37/1)
    - Southeast store opening, 1940 (Box-folder 37/2)
    - Southeast store exterior, circa 1950-1970 (Box-folder 37/3)
    - Sixth Avenue store exterior, 1951 (Box-folder 37/4)
    - Tigard store opening, undated (Box-folder 37/5)
    - Old Salem store, undated (Box-folder 37/6)
    - Stadium store opening, undated (Box-folder 37/7)
    - Stadium store exterior, 1930-1979 (Box-folder 37/8)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-104.
    - Stadium store interior, 1940-1979 (Box-folder 37/9)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-105.
    - Yamhill and 5th Store exterior, circa 1925-1940 (Box-folder 37/11)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-107 and 199-108.
    - Yamhill and 4th Store exterior, undated (Box-folder 37/12)
    - Walnut Park store exterior, 1940-1961 (Box-folder 37/13)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-109.
    - Walnut Park store interior, 1936; 1961; 1979 (Box-folder 37/14)
      Includes images of store grand re-opening in 1979.
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-110 and 199-111.
    - Astoria store (old) (Box-folder 37/15)
  - Washington State Stores, 1962-2008
    - Hazel Dell Grand Opening, 1962 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Hazel Dell Exterior, 1962 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Hazel Dell Grand Re-Opening, 1998 (Box-folder 16/3)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-035 through 199-036
    - Lynnwood Grand Opening, 1968 (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Lynnwood Exterior, 1968 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Lynnwood Interiors, 1968 (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Bellevue Remodel, circa 1980 (Box-folder 16/7)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-037
    - Puyallup Interior and Exterior, circa 1980 (Box-folder 16/8)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-034
    - Totem Lake Grand Opening, 1980 (Box-folder 16/9)
    - Bellingham Grand Opening and Remodel, 1974; 1984 (Box-folder 16/10)
      Negatives (from 1984) in Neg Folder 199-033
    - Bellingham Grand Opening Newspaper Section - Oversize (Original), 1974 (Box-folder OSD-3/2)
    - Bellingham Grand Opening Newspaper Section - Oversize (Photocopy), 1974 (Box-folder OSC-1/8)
    - Fourth Plain Remodel, 1981 (Box-folder 16/11)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-038
    - Everett Remodel, 1986 (Box-folder 16/12)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-039
    - Kent Groundbreaking, 1988 (Box-folder 16/13)
    - Auburn Grand Opening, 1989 (Box-folder 16/14)
    - Lacey Grand Opening, 1989 (Box-folder 16/15)
    - Kitsap Grand Opening, 1990 (Box-folder 16/16)
    - South Hill (Puyallup) Grand Opening, 1996 (Box-folder 16/17)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-040
    - Mill Creek Grand Opening, 1998 (Box-folder 16/18)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-041 and Advantix cartridge in Negative Box #2.
    - Wenatchee Grand Opening, 1999 (Box-folder 17/1)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-043 through 199-044
    - Ballard (Seattle) Grand Opening, 1999 (Box-folder 17/2 - 3)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-045 through 199-047
      Promotional magnets removed to the OHS Museum.
    - Salmon Creek Grand Opening, 1999 (Box-folder 17/4)
      Negatives in Advantix cartridge in Negative Box B.
      Color transparencies in Neg Folder 199-093.
    - Battle Ground Grand Opening, 2000 (Box-folder 17/5)
    - Port Orchard Grand Opening, 2000 (Box-folder 17/6)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-042
    - University Place (Seattle) Grand Opening, 2000 (Box-folder 17/7)
    - Bothell Grand Opening, 1968 (Box-folder 17/8)
    - Grand Central (Vancouver) Grand Opening, 2008 (Box-folder 17/9)
    - Grand Central (Vancouver) Grand Opening - Oversize Ad Inserts, 2008 (Box-folder OSD-3/2)
    - Redondo Grand Opening, 2008 (Box-folder 17/10)
    - Redondo Grand Opening - Oversize Ad Inserts, 2008 (Box-folder OSD-3/2)
    - Snohomish Grand Opening, 2008 (Box-folder 17/11)
    - Snohomish Grand Opening - Oversize Ad Inserts, 2008 (Box-folder OSD-3/2)
    - Everett Grand Opening, 2008 (Box-folder 17/12)
    - Marketime store (Seattle), circa 1965 (Box-folder 36/1)
    - Vancover store (old), 1935 (Box-folder 37/10)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-106.
  - Other States' Stores
    Files on stores in Alaska, Idaho, California and Utah.
    - Juneau, Alaska Grand Opening, 1986 (Box-folder 18/1)
    - West Fairbanks, Alaska Grand Opening and Remodel, 1991; 1998 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Wasilla, Alaska Grand Opening, 1996 (Box-folder 18/3)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-048 through 199-049 and Advantix cartridges in Negative Box #2.
    - Chico, California Grand Opening, 1990 (Box-folder 18/4)
    - Chico, California Grand Opening - Oversize Ad Inserts, 1990 (Box-folder OSD-3/2)
    - Idaho Falls Grand Opening, 1997 (Box-folder 18/5 - 6)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-050 through 199-056
    - Bountiful, Utah Grand Opening, 1998 (Box-folder 18/7)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-057 through 199-058 and Advantix cartridges in Negative Box #2.
- Annual Reports, 1960-1980; 1986-1997; Series D
  Fred Meyer, Inc. was privately held in the years 1981-1985 and therefore no annual reports were published in those years.
  - Annual Reports, 1960-1976 (Box-folder 19/1 - 17)
  - Annual Reports, 1977-1980; 1986-1990 (Box-folder 20/1 - 9)
  - Annual Reports, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 21/1 - 7)
- Employee Newsletters, 1949-2007; Series E
  Fred Meyer, Inc. has produced newsletters for employees throughout the years under various names: My-Te-Fine News, The Register, The Q-Municator and Fred Meyer Focus. The newsletters have been published on bi-weekly or monthly schedules at different times. No newsletters were published between 2001 and 2005.
  - My-Te-Fine News
    - 1949-1955 (Box-folder 22/1-6)
    - 1956-1959 (Box-folder 23/1-4)
    - 1960-1963 (Box-folder 24/1-4)
    - 1964-1968 (Box-folder 25/1-5)
    - 1969-1975 (Box-folder 26/1-6)
    - 1976-1979 (Box-folder 27/1-3)
  - The Fred Meyer Register
    - 1980-1982 (Box-folder 27/4-6)
    - 60th Anniversary Special Issues, 1982 (Box-folder 27/7)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 27/8)
    - 1984-1989 (Box-folder 28/1-6)
  - The Q-Municator
    - 1990-1996 (Box-folder 29/1-7)
    - 1997-1999 (Box-folder 30/1-7)
    - 2000-2001 (Box-folder 31/1-3)
  - The Fred Meyer Focus, 2005-2008 (Box-folder 31/4-7)
- Promotions and Advertising, Series F
  - Miscellaneous Promotions, 1930s (Box-folder 32/1)
    Photographs of various promotions and sales throughout Fred Meyer Stores in the 1930s.
    Negatives in Neg Folders 199-094, 199-095 and 199-096.
    Some images also represented in contact sheets in 12/5.
  - Miscellaneous Displays, circa 1930-1945 (Box-folder 32/2)
    Photographs of various merchandise displays throughout Fred Meyer Stores in the 1930s and 1940s.
  - Evolution of Shopping Carts, circa 1935 (Box-folder 32/3)
    Photo collection of various types of shopping carts.
    Negative in Neg Folder 199-097.
  - My-Te-Fine Family, circa 1935 (Box-folder 32/4)
    Promotional photograph of family shopping at Fred Meyer.
  - Business Education Day, circa 1935; 1969 (Box-folder 32/5)
    Photograph from 1930s event; itinerary and memos from 1969 event.
  - Coupon Books, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 32/6)
  - Coffee Days Promotion, 1938 (Box-folder 32/7)
  - Fred Meyer Smoker (Boxing event), circa 1938; circa 1942 (Box-folder 32/8)
  - Miscellaneous Promotions, 1940-1963 (Box-folder 32/9)
    Photographs of various promotions and sales throughout Fred Meyer Stores in the 1940s-1960s. Folder includes list of all events.
  - Fred Meyer Surprise Night, 1940 (Box-folder 32/10)
    Photo of Oriental Theater, Portland, Oregon.
  - Flood Relief, 1937 (Box-folder 32/11)
    Fred Meyer donation to the American Red Cross.
  - Fred Meyer Kids' Day at the Oriental Theater, circa 1940 (Box-folder 32/12)
  - Professor Quiz Whiz, circa 1941 (Box-folder 32/13)
  - Sunshine Division, 1941 (Box-folder 32/14)
    Food distribution to the needy.
  - Milk Fund, circa 1942 (Box-folder 32/15)
  - War Bond Auction, 1942 (Box-folder 32/16)
  - War Bond Promotion, 1942 (Box-folder 32/17)
  - War Bond Drive, 1943 (Box-folder 32/18)
  - 4-H Rose Bush Promotion, 1943 (Box-folder 32/19)
  - Peacock Gift to the Portland Zoo, 1943 (Box-folder 32/20)
  - Volunteer Berry Pickers, 1945 (Box-folder 32/21)
  - Victory Garden Show, 1945 (Box-folder 32/22)
  - Cosmetics Class, 1946 (Box-folder 32/23)
  - Montavilla Garden Show, 1947 (Box-folder 32/24)
  - Phillip Morris's "Johnny", 1949 (Box-folder 32/25)
  - Outdoor Advertising - Oversize, circa 1950; circa 1990 (Box-folder OSD-1/6)
  - Ambulance Corps, circa 1950 (Box-folder 32/26)
  - Fred Meyer Rose Festival Float, circa 1950 (Box-folder 32/27)
    Two copies of negative in Neg Folder 199-098.
    Image also represented on contact sheet in 12/5.
  - My-Te-Fine Dog Show, 1951 (Box-folder 33/1)
  - Gift Days, 1953 (Box-folder 33/2)
  - Shriners Square Dance, 1954 (Box-folder 33/3)
  - Let's Go to the Races, 1945 (Box-folder 33/4)
    Event at the Oriental Theater in Portland.
  - Jersey Milk Campaign, 1952 (Box-folder OSE-7/1)
    Scrapbook detailing radio, newspaper, store and outdoor promotions for Jersey milk in 1952.
  - Coupon Books, 1952-1953; 1963 (Box-folder 33/5)
  - Wisconsin Cheese Promotions, 1963; 1965 (Box-folder 33/6)
  - Outdoor Advertising, circa 1968 (Box-folder 33/7)
  - General Merchandise Catalog, 1975 (Box-folder 33/8)
  - General Merchandise Catalog, 1976 (Box-folder 33/9)
  - Coupon Books, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 33/10)
  - Fred Meyer Logos, 1930-2000 (Box-folder 34/1)
  - Fred Meyer Logos - Oversize, 1930-2000 (Box-folder OSD-1/6)
    Timeline poster of all Fred Meyer logos used throughout the years.
  - Price Comparison Ads, 1980s (Box-folder 34/2)
  - Price Comparison and Total Minimum Pricing Ads - Oversize (photocopies), 1980s (Box-folder OSD-4/1)
  - Price Comparison and Total Minimum Pricing Ads - Oversize (originals), 1980s (Box-folder OSD-4/2)
  - Quick Draw Charlie, circa 1980 (Box-folder 34/3)
  - Run Between the States, 1983 (Box-folder 34/4)
  - Fred Bear - images, circa 1985 (Box-folder 34/5)
    Color transparencies in Neg Folder 199-099.
  - Fred Bear - letters, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 34/6)
    Letters to Fred Bear received during holiday contests.
  - Fred Meyer 10K Run, 1985 (Box-folder 34/7)
    Negatives in Neg Folder 199-059
  - Founder's Day Sale - Oversize Ad Inserts, 1986-1990 (Box-folder OSD-3/4)
  - Salvation Army Gift-Giving, circa 1990 (Box-folder 34/8)
    Photographs, pamphlets and promotional coloring books produced for Fred Meyer's fundraising for the Salvation Army.
  - Oregon Convention Center Opening, 1990 (Box-folder 34/9)
    Promotional materials given away at the grand opening of the Oregon Convention Center.
  - Fred Meyer Bumper Sticker, circa 1990 (Box-folder 35/1)
  - Total Minimum Pricing Ads - Oversize, 1990s (Box-folder OSD-4/3)
  - Fred Meyer Golf Challenge, 1990 (Box-folder 35/2)
    Negatives in Neg Folders 199-060 through 199-066 and Advantix cartridge in Negative Box #2.
  - Great Food Ad Inserts - Oversize, 1991-1992 (Box-folder OSB-1/1-4)
  - Great Food Ad Inserts - Oversize, 1992-1993 (Box-folder OSB-2/1-4)
  - Cycle Oregon, 1992 (Box-folder 35/3)
    Photograph of Fred Meyer truck with Cycle Oregon promotion.
  - Price Comparison Ads, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 35/4)
  - 75th Anniversary Sale, 1997 (Box-folder 35/5)
  - Anniversary Sales - Oversize Ad Inserts (originals), 1997-2008 (Box-folder OSD-3/3)
  - Star Quest, 1997 (Box-folder 35/6)
    Photographs from a Caribbean cruise vacation for Fred Meyer employees who were winners of a customer service incentive program.
    Negatives in Neg Folders 199-067 through 199-068
  - Nike World Masters Games, 1997 (Box-folder 35/7)
    Sample invitation and envelope with sponsorship logos.
  - Cook & Tell, 1999 (Box-folder 35/8)
    (Videotape demonstrations removed to OHS Film and Video Archive.)
    Materials for Fred Meyer in-store cooking classes.
  - Lucky Buck Sale Signs - Oversize, circa 2000 (Box-folder OSD-1/6)
  - Reward Card Ad Artwork, circa 2000 (Box-folder 35/9)
  - 85th and 86th Anniversary Sales - letters, 2007-2008 (Box-folder 35/10-35/11)
    Letters and emails sent in during a contest in which customers were asked to write about their favorite Fred Meyer memories.
  - 85th and 86th Anniversary Sales - advertisements, 2007-2008 (Box-folder 35/12)
  - Responsible Choices - letters and advertisements, 2008 (Box-folder 35/13)
    Letters from customers who were asked to send in their suggestions for environmentally friendly grocery shopping practices. Winning ideas were published in Fred Meyer ads.
  - Responsible Choices - Oversize Ad Inserts, 2008 (Box-folder OSD-1/6)
  - Newspaper Advertising Scrapbooks, 1934-1982
    Oversize boxes containing newspaper clippings of Fred Meyer advertisements.
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, December 14, 1934 - May 24, 1935 (Box-folder OSG-1/1-2)
    - Out-Of-Town Newspaper Ads, February 3, 1939 - September 22, 1939 (Box-folder OSG-1/3-4)
      Ads primarily from Astoria and Salem.
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, March 16, 1937 - September 25, 1937 (Box-folder OSE-2/1-3)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, September 1943 - November 1943 (Box-folder OSE-3/1)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, November 1943 - January 1944 (Box-folder OSE-4/1)
    - Astoria & Salem Newspaper Ads, September 18, 1942 - February 12, 1943 (Box-folder OSG-2/1-3)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, May 19, 1942 - April 13, 1943 (Box-folder OSG-3/1-4)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, April 13, 1952 - July 17, 1952 (Box-folder OSE-5/1-2)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, July 17, 1952 - October 30, 1952 (Box-folder OSE-5/3-4)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, July 17, 1952 - October 30, 1952 (Box-folder OSE-6/1-2)
    - Portland and Seattle Newspaper Ads, August 24, 1952 - October 24, 1952 (Box-folder OSE-6/3-5)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, February 24, 1958 - May 1, 1958 (Box-folder OSG-4/1)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, February 28, 1963 - May 5, 1963 (Box-folder OSE-8/1-3)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, September 2, 1964 - November 1, 1964 (Box-folder OSE-9/1-3)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, September 13, 1972 - October 27, 1972 (Box-folder OSG-6/1)
    - Portland Newspaper Ads, November 1979 - February 1980 (Box-folder OSE-10/1)
    - Tacoma and Puyallup Newspaper Ads, 1982 (Box-folder OSE-11/1-2)
- Negatives and Transparencies, circa 1925-2001; Series G
  Contains negatives and transparencies, most of which are represented as prints and prinouts in the rest of the collection.
  Access to this series is restricted.
  - (Box-folder Neg Box 199-A)
    Contains Neg Folders 001-041.
  - (Box-folder Neg Box 199-B)
    Contains Neg Folders 042-068 and 10 Advantix cartridges.
  - (Box-folder Neg Box 199-C)
    Contains Neg Folders 069-111.